Hi everyone, I'm Lorena
and I'm Phillip.
and welcome back to...
Break It Kids!
your movement break for your brain, body...
and senses.
Break It Kids!
Today, we've got a very special mission.
A whole lot of different types of fruit have gotten lost in Candyland,
and we need to save them from all that sugar.
Now, a little bit of sugar is OK,
but a whole land made of
sugar?
That's just too much.
Luckily, we have a map to help us find our way.
But first,
as always,
we fire it up.
Let's get rescuing.
Now, according to our map,
the bananas are stuck in the candy cane and lollipop forest.
Let's head there first.
Wow, these candy canes are so tall,
and the bananas are stuck right at the top.
How did they even get there?
To get the bananas down,
we're going to shake the candy cane just like this
as hard as you can, moving your whole body.
And then as the bananas fall,
we're going to do star jumps on the spot j
just like this.
And then they're going to plop into our magic bag.
Ready, kids?
Let's go. OK,
start with the shaking.
Move your whole body.
That's a big candy cane. Come on.
Here they come. Ready?
Catch them. There's one.
Come on, kids.
We have to keep moving.
That's two. Yes, kids.
OK, last one on this one.
Ready?
Caught it, yes.
Into our bag, nice and safe.
Let's move to the next candy cane.
OK, here it is.
Ready, and shake as hard as you can.
Come on, move your whole body.
Remember, this is far enough. Let's go, let's go.
OK, they're loose.
Star jumps.
Here we go.
That's one.
Come on, kids.
That's two.
Remember, this is far enough.
And the last one's on its way.
Come on.
Almost there.
And we got them. Yes, kids.
Into our bag, nice and safe.
Now it's time to split
and head to the next area.
Now the map says the apples are at the top of Mount Gumdrop.
We're going to have to get all the way to the top
to save them.
But there's one big problem.
Gumdrops are rolling down as we're going to go up.
We're going to have to miss them all
and get right to the top.
To do that,
we're going to sprint on the spot just like this,
as quick as you can.
And then,
as the gumdrops come,
we're going to hop over them, just like this.
Follow me,
and we can do this.
Ready, kids?
Let's go.
OK,
we're going to have to start quick.
This is a big mountain. So the faster we go,
the quicker we can get to the top.
And remember, this is
So let me give you max energy. Come on, kids.
OK, now come the first gumdrops.
Ready, hop,
and again, hop,
and again, hop.
Last one.
Excellent work, kids. Now sprint again.
Come on, let's go, let's go, let's go.
All the way to the top.
Here we go, we're halfway.
Wow, this is tough.
More gumdrops. Ready,
hop, sprint again.
More gumdrops, hop,
hop again,
and again.
OK, last little bit.
I can see one or two more gumdrops left.
Come on,
last one now, hop,
and again, hop,
and last little bit,
and we made it.
Look at that.
The apples are all safe.
I guess they're just enjoying the nice view.
Come on, guys.
Into the bag, please.
Now the next fruit on the map are mangoes, and it looks like they're hiding in a cupcake maze.
Hmm,
those are some pretty cheeky mangoes.
To find them, we're going to do scissor kicks on the spot like this,
and then you're going to follow my directions.
We're either going to go straight,
to the left, or
to the right.
Ready, kids, let's go.
OK,
this is a big maze, so we're going to have to use max effort to find them all.
OK, to the left,
there we go.
Wow, that's a lot of cupcakes.
And to the right.
Excellent, kids.
And straight.
There's the first one.
Speed up, come on.
Come on, you little cheeky mango.
You're not going to get away from us.
And we got him, yes!
Into the bag.
OK, turn left.
Oh, this is tough work, isn't it?
And to the right.
Here we go.
Straight again.
And to the left.
Come on, kids,
there's another one!
Speed it up. Let's go, let's go.
Come on, cheeky mango, we're going to get you.
And we got him, yes.
Into the bag.
OK, straight now.
And then to the right.
Come on, kids, this is fired up. Let's go.
And straight again.
There's the last one.
Speed up, come on.
And we got him.
Yes, kids.
Into the bag.
Glad those cheeky mangoes are in our bag.
Now to get out of here.
Time to focus it.
Unpeel your brain.
According to our map, the grapes are on Candy Floss Lane. Let's head over.
Oh no,
it looks like our little grape friends are stuck in a
sticky floss.
Let's help them out.
To do that, we're going to bounce on one leg like this,
reach down,
grab our little grape friend
and put it in the bag.
And then
repeat on the other side,
just like this.
Excellent, let's go.
Okay, balancing here,
maximum focus.
All right, let's reach down to grab the grape.
Go, you got him.
Yes,
okay, first one done.
Other side.
Now this takes maximum effort.
Let's go.
Go, whoa,
it's a bit wobbly.
Yes,
okay, now this floss is sticky,
so come on,
stick with me.
Okay, balancing here.
Get that little grape.
Oh, it's so sticky.
Yes,
okay, here's another one.
Okay, we've got to be gentle, they're just grapes.
Don't squeeze too hard.
There we go, okay.
Two more,
balancing here.
Reach down,
that's it, and one more.
Yes,
these silly grapes, they should never be allowed to wander around all by themselves.
I'm glad we got them all.
According to the map, our last fruit, the pineapple, is bobbing around in the chocolate river.
Now,
I've got an idea.
Let's hop on our chocolate slab
and use a lollipop to row them out
before they get way too soggy.
To do that,
kneel just like this,
and then take your giant lollipop
and row on either side of your body just like this to get the pineapples out.
Ready, kids? Let's go.
All right, hold on to your lollipop.
Let's start rowing.
That's it.
Okay, now this is tricky.
So again, focus it, kids.
Side to side across the body just like that.
Oh, there's our first pineapple.
Yes, we got it.
Excellent.
I mean, it looks like a pineapple spot here.
They look so relaxed in this chocolate river.
And I'm not gonna lie,
I could do with a cheeky taste.
There we go, another one.
Excellent, keep it up.
All right, let's row a little bit faster.
Come on, everyone.
There's another one.
Yes, well done.
It's a bit wobbly.
Keep your tummy tight.
Try not to fall in.
Let's go. Come on, everyone.
Oh, this chocolate looks so yummy.
Keep it up.
Yes, we got the last one.
Great rowing, kids. We have them all.
And we used a chocolate slab and a lollipop.
How cool.
Well done, team. We've saved all the fruit.
Now, according to the map, the only way to get out of Candyland and to keep these fruits safe is to go across the Biscuit Bridge.
Sounds pretty cool. All right, let's grab the bag, everyone.
Oh, it's heavy. Come on.
Yes.
Now, I've got a bit of a crazy idea.
We made it across the Biscuit Bridge,
but what if we now smash the Biscuit Bridge
to keep all of our fruit nice and safe
and to keep them from sneaking in all the time?
Luckily, we've got this Popsicle as a hammer
that we can use to smash it.
All right, to do that, we're gonna pick up our Popsicle
and then do a figure of eight
just like this,
and then squat down,
smash the bridge just like that.
Ready, kids? Let's go.
All right, pick up your Popsicle.
Figure of eight, nice and controlled.
And get ready to smash.
Squat, smash.
Excellent.
Okay, this is a really strong bridge.
Spending maximum effort.
Ready, squat.
Boom.
Okay, not yet.
Come on, everyone. We've gotta keep the fruit safe
and the Candyland residents
Squat, smash.
That's it, keep it up.
Figure of eight, nice and controlled.
Can't believe we have a Popsicle as a hammer.
This is too cool.
Here we go, it's starting to crumble.
That's it, keep it up.
And use all your strength.
Boom,
nice.
Okay, one more time. Come on, it's almost there.
We've almost broken it. Ready?
Yes, there it goes.
Great work, kids.
That biscuit bridge didn't stand a
And some would say that's how the biscuit crumbles.
Now that was a fruit-alicious adventure.
But now it's time
to cool it.
For our first cool it exercise,
we're going to do sunshine breath.
So you can imagine you're a big, warm, bright sun.
Sitting in a comfortable position, just like this,
you can breathe in through your nose.
Imagine you're that sun that's just getting bigger.
And then as you breathe out through your mouth,
you're going to spread your warm rays of sunshine all over.
Ready, kids? Let's go.
In through your nose.
And then breathe out through your mouth.
Imagine those rays spreading all around you.
Go again. In through your nose.
And out through your mouth.
Imagine the rays getting brighter and warmer each time you breathe out.
Let's go again.
You can also send those sunshine rays to someone that you love.
In through your nose.
And out through your mouth.
What a great way to calm your mind and body down.
And you get to spread some sunshine around.
Excellent work.
For our final cool it exercise,
we're going to do cat-cow breathing.
To do that, we're going to go down onto all fours,
just like this.
And then when you breathe in through your nose,
you're going to arch your back and look up like a cow.
And then when you breathe out through your mouth,
you're going to arch your back the other way like a cat.
Super simple.
Ready, kids? Let's go.
Breathing in through your nose.
And then all the way out through your mouth.
Arch your back.
Remember to tuck your chin in.
Let's try again.
In through your nose.
And out through your mouth.
You can close your eyes if you want to.
Ready?
In through your nose.
And out through your mouth.
It's like a good stretch and breathing at the same time.
In through your nose.
And out through your mouth.
Excellent work, kids.
That's a great stretch to do any time.
Well done.
Now, remember to always keep an eye on your fruit.
You never know if they might wander off.
See you soon.
Break it, kids.